

- anuprita.ranade@outlook.com
- +91 8008545761
- anupritaranade
- in www.linkedin.com/in/anupritaranade

PROFILE

I am a creative individual who loves observing people to understand cultures and lifestyles. I use design as a tool to create delightful and human-centered experiences that fit seamlessly into people's lifestlyes. My experience encompasses a diverse range of areas such as UX/UI design, packaging, branding, user research, design strategy and industrial design. I read a lot of books and I love to draw and paint.



EDUCATION

MIT Institute of Design 2009-2014

Bachelors in Product Design

Rochester Institute of Technology 2015

MFA Furniture Design (dropped out)



EXPERTISE

Design thinking, strategy, wireframes, usability auditing, visual design, illustration, web design, digital app design (iOS and Android), Wordpress

SOFTWARES

- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe InDesign
- Sketch
- Rhinoceros CATIA
- SolidWorks



CERTIFICATION

CUA (Certified Usability Analyst) -Human Factors International

EXPERIENCE

Mutual Mobile Solutions Pvt Ltd (2016 to present)

Interaction and Visual Designer

- I lead the design efforts and work with developers, project managers and quality assurance engineers to create digital experiences for iOS, Android and web applications
- I communicate with clients to guage their product requirements and business goals in order to create designs that cater to their specific needs
- My job involves educating my peers about the design process and driving them to have a user-centered approach towards the products we build as a team

Youth for Seva (2014 to present)

Volunteer

- I take out time outside work to do this as I am passionate about applying design thinking and creative techniques in the field of education
- I use experential learning techniques to teach English, Science and Mathematics to underprivileged students in government schools
- I conduct Spoken English workshops for students where I teach students ways to speak English fluently
- I designed brochures and promotional material for Youth for Seva's events
- I Youth for Seva organize various events such as cultural fests for kids, blood donation drives and menstrual hygiene awareness for adolescent girls

Infomate Data Systems (2013 to 2014)

Product and retail space designer

- I worked as a space designer and my job involved visual merchandising, designing kiosks, banners, posters and promotional material for display at trade fairs.
- I designed stationery products for office use

Deep Red Ink

Design Researcher My work at Deep Red Ink revolved around user

research and creating design strategies to impact business and help them achieve their targets.

PROJECTS

Seagate Mobile Toolkit

Mobile Toolkit is an app for iOS and Android that allows you to manage files and folders on your Seagate hard drive using only your mobile device. It has features that allow your to back up your mobile's data such as photos, music, videos, documents etc to the hard drive. Leading the design efforts for this project, my work involved:

- 1. Active communication with product owners from Seagate to understand the requirements and functionality of the hard drive. 2. Designing wireframes and visuals for both iOS and Android versions.
- 3. Working with developers and quality assurance engineers for implementing the designs



The Nutribullet Balance app syncs with the Nutribullet Blender via bluetooth and tracks nutritional

Nutribullet Balance

information based on the ingredients you add while making a smoothie. For this project, I: 1. Worked with designers and product owners from Nutribullet to create wireframes.

- 2. Worked with designers from Mutual Mobile to create visual designs

Available on App Store



Available on Play Store

IRCTC- App Audit IRCTC is a subsidiary of the Indian Railways that handles the online ticketing process. The goal of this

project was to analyse the usability of the IRCTC ticket booking app (Android) and suggest enhancements for improving the efficiency of ticket booking. It involved: 1. Conducting user testing for various features of the app

- 2. Doing a thorough Heuristic review of the app
- 3. Identifying potential areas for improving user experience 4. Creating wireframes to solve the identified problems

Available on Play Store

NMMS - Youth for Seva

IRCTC is a subsidiary of the Indian Railways that handles the online ticketing process. The goal of this project was to analyse the usability of the IRCTC ticket booking app (Android) and suggest enhancements for improving the efficiency of ticket booking. It involved:

- 1. Conducting user testing for various features of the app
- 2. Doing a thorough Heuristic review of the app 3. Identifying potential areas for improving user experience
- 4. Creating wireframes to solve the identified problems